A landscape of lust and cunning.
The Draughtsman's Contract is a history, mystery,
comedy film directed by Peter Greenaway.
A young artist is commissioned by the wife of a wealthy landowner to make a
series of drawings of the estate while her husband is away.
Mr. Neville, played by Anthony Higgins.
Virginia Herbert, played by Janet Suzman.
Herbert, played by Dave Hill.
Sarah Talmann, played by Anne-Louise Lambert.
Mr. Talmann, played by Hugh Fraser.
Thomas Noyes, played by Neil Cunningham.
The Draughtsman's Contract is a 1982 British period drama film written and directed by Peter Greenaway –
his first conventional feature film (following the feature-length mockumentary The Falls).
Originally produced for Channel 4, the film is a form of murder mystery, set in rural
Wiltshire, England in 1694 (during the joint reign of William III and Mary II).
The period setting is reflected in Michael Nyman's score, which borrows widely from Henry Purcell, and in the
extensive and elaborate costume designs (which, for effect, slightly exaggerate those of the period).
The action was shot on location in the house and
formal gardens of Groombridge Place.
The film received the Grand Prix of the Belgian Film Critics Association.
The film explores themes of adultery, drawing and
painting, witshire, southhampton, 17th century.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.